怪獣
Right, it's so simple.
珍獣
I merely need to fix him.
財宝
I only need the power to do that.
秘宝
The question is how we will manage to win.
魔境
If anyone has any brilliant ideas,
I'd like to hear them.
秘境
You're simply awful.
「未知」という言葉が放つ魔力 その力に魅せられた すごい奴らがいる
When you asked us to join, did you not
already have an answer in mind?
人は　彼らを…
We exterminate the Ants
in silence, one at a time.
「ハンター」と呼ぶ
Come on, what are you doing? You'll never defeat Knuckle and Shoot,
much less the Chimera Ants, like this.
「念」によって封印されていた 箱の中には 謎のアイテムが３つ
Promise x And x Reunion
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　やっぱり　お前も ハンターになっちまったか。 これが　親父の声… [ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　それで　１つ 聞きたいことがある。
As the Queen prepares for the King's birth, she requires the equivalent of two hundred
and fifty human meatballs per day to give birth to a strong King.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　会う気があるなら このまま聞いてくれ。 [ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　もし　その気がないなら 停止ボタンを押せばいい。
It moved.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　イエスってことか それじゃ　もう一度　聞くぜ。 [ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　覚悟は　あるか？
continue their training so they
can defeat Knuckle and Shoot, take their tokens, and return to NGL.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　はぁ…　そんなに会いたいか。
Will this really be enough for
them to execute the plan
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　俺は　お前に会いたくない。 [ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　どの面　下げて会えばいいのか 分からねえしな。
to slaughter Morel's disciples?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ろくなもんじゃねえ。
Okay, all done!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　俺が　これを吹き込んでから お前が聞くことになる日まで
You finally lasted for three hours. We did it...
最低１０年以上の時を 経ているだろう。
That was hard! I can't move an inch...
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　だが　その間 絶対に変わらないものがある。
What are you talking about? Stand up. We're going out. Huh?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　俺が　俺であることだ。
Wh-Why? See? You can move. Let's go!
ボ！ ボォ！
Tell us why we're going to see Knuckle.
ボォ！
Jeez, don't ask questions
with obvious answers. To fight him!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　だから　お前が このテープを聞いている今も
What are you talking about? We still have time. What if we lose?
どこかでバカをやっている。
You just try again. Huh?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　それでも会いたきゃ 捜してくれ。
Whether you win or lose isn't important.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　だが　さっきも言ったが 俺は　お前とは会いたくねえ。
All that matters is who ends
up with the tokens, right? Yeah.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　近づくのが分かったら とんずら　かますぜ。
Which means you must take theirs. If it looks like you'll lose, run.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　捕まえてみろよ お前もハンターなんだろ？
Then try again the next day. From here on, you'll practice
Ren for three hours a day.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　聞きたければ このまま聞いてくれ。 [ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　別に　いいなら…。
Still a no show, huh?
いいのか？ うん。
Your owner's really bad...
でも　もしかしたら　何か 手掛かりがあるかもしれないぜ。
Hey, stop it!
ないよ　多分　勘だけど。
That tickles. Cut it out!
それに言ったろ？ 俺の母親は　ミトさん！
Hey, come on...
えぇ!?　デッキにオーラが!?
Is that Knuckle?
「念」だ！ 「念」でテープを巻き戻してる！
Yeah.
「念」？　まさか　今どこかで!? 違う　「念」を込めたんだよ １０年以上前に。
No way...
停止ボタンを押したら 巻き戻すように。 何で？ さぁな。
They're the other candidates?
そうか　消す気だ　自分の声を！ えぇ!? ダメだ　止められない！　クソ！
Guess they must not respect me...
ダメだ　止まらねえ！ コンセント抜いたのに!? 悪いな　ゴン　壊すぜ！
If I'm being compared to a couple of kids, they must not think I'm very strong...
クソ！　ダメだ！ 「念」でガードしてやがる！
Such an intimidating presence...
終わったみたいだね。 はぁ…。
Were you just out swimming or something, eh?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　今度は　録音ボタンが入った！
You kids can never defeat me.
やっぱ　ダビング用のテープも やられてる。
S-Stupid... Wh-Why would I cry?
何で　ここまでする必要が あったのかな？
I'm not upset about this.
手掛かりを残したくなかった ってことだろうな。
Th-Th-These are just, well, uh...
手掛かりって？
Tears from laughing too much, fool.
音声からだけでも 相当のデータが得られるんだ。 そうなの？
I'll kill you, get it? So don't tell anyone!
録音した人間の身長や体重 性別　年齢　顔のつくり
Punch me!
持病も分かるし 心理状態だって読み取れる。
Huh? I'll show you how much stronger I really am.
へぇ。 背景の雑音から　録音した場所も 特定できることもあるしな。
And you'll realize that I don't need
to bother dodging your punches.
でも　警戒したのは もっと別のことだぜ。
Hit me as many times as you like.
別なことって？ 念能力だよ。
But if I don't take a step from this spot, leave your tokens behind.
機械より はるかに優秀な解析ができる
This is the best chance you'll have!
念能力の持ち主がいても おかしくないだろ？
You kids would need a hundred years
before you could try fighting me!
例えば　声を聞いただけで 相手の全てが分かる能力とか。 そうか。
You're the one who challenged us to a duel.
お前の親父　手ごわいな。
Don't look down on us! I'd like to respond that way...
うん。 それにしても　テープが ダメになっちまったから
But it's clear that we aren't on Knuckle's level.
手掛かりは ２つになっちまったな。
We have no right to argue that.
指輪と　ロムカードか。 指輪は　ともかく 問題は　このロムカードだな。
Not right now...
うん　これ　普通のより小さいね。 これ専用のハードがあるのかな？
The fact is, we can't overcome everything with willpower.
『ジョイステ』？
We can't argue with him...
『ジョイステーション』って ゲーム機　３世代前の。 お前　なんも知らねえのな。
But we don't have to accept it!
きっと　あるぜ おもちゃ屋って　あるか？ うん　あるけど…。
I won't stop hitting you until you move.
よし　待ってろ。 え？
Enough talk... Just get to it.
あら　どこ行くの？ おもちゃ屋！
First comes rock!
港の外れだよ！ 分かってる！
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
気をつけてね！
What's with the intense aura?
へぇ これが『ジョイステーション』。
If I guess wrong, I could die...
懐かしいな　昔よくやったぜ 隠れた名作も　いっぱいあるし。
Come on... I'd expect him to attack the belly.
ふん このロムカードも名作なのかな？
Yeah, that's the only real choice. Gotta be the belly.
タイトルとか何も書いてないけど。
Rock... Yeah, it's the belly!
お前　本当に ゲームやったことないんだな。
Belly! Belly! Belly!
貴重な奴。
Paper...
そう？ これはゲームソフトじゃ　ない。
Rock!
どうやら　入ってるゲームは １つだけだな。 『グリードアイランド』って ゲームらしい。
Knuckle-san?
『グリードアイランド』？
You okay?
それにしても すごいデータ量だぜ。 無駄だと思うけど 一応　データをコピーしとくぜ。 [TV]　『グリードアイランド』をコピーします。 さて…。
I... trusted... you...
ネットだよ ゲーム名が分かったんだ。 売ってる店を検索する。
What's with him?
え！　１件もないのかよ！
Obviously, he's a total idiot.
つまり　個人が作ったゲームでさ もともと　売り物じゃないか
Oh, are you awake?
何かの事情で　発売禁止に なってるゲームってことさ。
You're stronger than I thought.
とにかく調べてみるか。
Guess I underestimated you...
「『グリードアイランド』 ハンター専用　ハンティングゲーム」。
Why didn't you take this?
ハンター専用？ しかも　何だ　この値段！ ５億８０００万!?
You should've taken the
token and ditched me.
５８億だ！ えっ？
We don't want your token.
しっかし　何ちゅう でたらめな値段なんだ。 販売個数は１００個だって これって　多くないよね？
We want the strength to defeat
you in a straight-up fight.
すっげぇ少ねえよ ぜってぇナメてる　少な過ぎるぜ！
Could I ask you something? Sure, go ahead.
けど　分かった 値段は　とんでもねえけど
Why did you become a Beast Hunter?
ハンターなら買える値段だし こりゃ　完全な売り切れだ。
Huh? It's a long story...
制作元に　在庫は　ないのかな？
And it brings back bad memories.
そうだな 一応　問い合わせてみるか。
Then, why did you volunteer for the punitive force?
[TEL] お尋ねのソフトですが そちらは　もう 絶版になっております。
Simply put, to keep it from doing its job.
[TEL]　申し訳ありませんが 再生産の予定もございません。
I don't like the idea of cutting off
whatever doesn't fit the mold.
そうですか　どうも。
My teacher says I'm just a softy.
やっぱりダメだった。 うん　持ってる人を捜し出して 譲ってもらうしかないのかな？
But you can't judge something that
you've never seen before...
だな　ネットの逆オークションに 告知して
First, you have to exchange blows.
売ってくれる奴が名乗り出るのを 待つってのがセオリーだ。
And you'll get yourself killed in the process!
闘技場で稼いだ金 ２人合わせても８億くらいか。
You're a good kid. Now that we've fought, I see that.
あと５０億かぁ…。
You, too. Huh?
市場価格より　高い金を 要求されるなんてザラだもん。 じゃあ　もっと高いってこと？ かもな。
You! He wouldn't leave your side.
うん。 うん。 まぁ　ダメもとで 告知だけしとこうよ。
They say good Hunters are well-liked by animals.
値段　要相談」。
S-Stupid! I'm not crying... Don't tell anyone!
額が額だから 考えてみりゃ　当たり前か。 お手上げだな。
Morel's student...
これ　一つ一つとなんて 交渉してられねえぞ。 第一　本物か偽物かも 俺達じゃ　判断つかねえし。
It's good!
情報も豊富になるけど 俺も　あんま詳しくねえしなぁ。
Fight me any time you want. Huh?
ゲームやネットに詳しい人って 誰か　いないの？
I'll give you as many tries as you want. But it's impossible for you to beat me
あっ…　いた　両方　詳しい奴。 えっ？
in the twenty days left.
えっ　本当？
Good stuff.
今？　どこでもいいだろ。 お前に言うと　おふくろに 伝わるかもしんないし。
What is this smoke?
ヤダよ 出掛けてるって言っとけよ。
Where am I?
ウソつけよ　あいつが 外出するわけねえじゃん！
All right...
てめぇのフィギュア 全部　ぶっ壊すって伝えてよ！
Let's begin, then.
分かったよ　つなげろ。
What? Chiona's squadron is missing?
おい　キル！
Yes...
言っとくけど　俺のコレクションに 指一本でも触れたら　殺すぞ！
Is it similar to what happened
to Reikei's squadron? It appears so.
冗談だよ　兄貴 怒んないでよ　怖いなぁ。 兄貴？
The leader disappeared first, and then the rest vanished, one by one.
それで？　何なんだ？ 忙しいのに　もう！
Well, that is the logical conclusion.
『グリードアイランド』？ ああ　知ってる。
We've been cutting down on
the number of soldiers, and our prey has begun to scatter.
お前の口から　そんなレアゲームの 名前が出るとは思わなかったな。
If humans target us during an extended hunt, it could be trouble.
持ってないのか？ [TEL]　ああ　持ってない 欲しかったけどさ
Should we ask the Queen to move the castle?
発売当時　俺　５歳だぜ 金なかったし。
No, we can't trouble the Queen right now.
１００本限定の販売に　申し込みが ２万件以上あったらしいぜ。
Then we ask Neferpitou-dono to investigate?
５８億ジェニーの 現金一括販売のみだったのにさ。
That idea doesn't thrill me...
持ち主さえ特定できない。 いろんな意味で伝説のゲームだよ。
I'll let you handle things outside...
[TEL]　で　何？ お前　もしかして探してんのか？
We'll protect the inside of the castle.
まぁね。 [TEL]　無理　無理　やめとけよ 俺でさえ諦めたんだから。
I'll try to strengthen this.
へぇ　兄貴が手も足も出ないで 降参してんのか。
Just as I expected... Well, at least she doesn't issue
any strange orders on a whim.
フン　昔の話だよ 今は心当たりくらいあるさ。
We should start by determining
our current troop strength.
ただ　労力と金額を考えると そこまでして欲しいゲームでも ないしなってことだよ。
How many Squadron Leaders remain? Assuming Chiona was taken out, twenty-eight.
ふん その心当たりってのを教えてよ。 [TEL]　はぁ？　タダじゃ　イヤだね。
Each Squadron Leader has four or five officers...
『グリードアイランド』のメモリーカードと交換 ってのは　どう？
And each officer commands
ten to fifteen soldiers.
どういうことだ？ [TEL]　ちょっとしたコネでさ ロムカードだけ手に入れたんだよ。 [TEL]　兄貴なら このデータを解析して
Some squadrons are under tight control, but many are free to wander around.
ソフト自体　再生することも できるんじゃないの？ その話　本当だろうな？
The missing four squadrons fall
under the latter category...
[TEL]　取引でウソつくほど 俗ぼけしてねえよ。
Of the remaining squadrons,
over half lack discipline.
[TEL]　分かった 心当たりは２つある。
And none will heed a warning.
ちょっと待った ケータイじゃ　ヤバいだろ？ 安心しろよ。
They've become arrogant since learning Nen.
盗聴されたって　そいつが どうこうできるレベルじゃ　ない。
Then we could use them to lay a trap.
ああ…　ああ　そうか。
I'm sure that's what's currently going
through the enemy's mind...
ＯＫ　分かった　ロムカードは いつもの方法で送る。
Well, we should be able to
continue the current plan.
悪ぃ！　話の流れでカードのコピーと 交換ってことにしちゃった。
Knov and I will be able to tell
once a trap has been laid.
うん　構わないよ　コピーだったら。 その代わり ２つの有力情報を得たぜ。
In fact, I believe we should
spring a few of those traps.
まず　１つ。 ハンターだけがアクセスできる ハンター専用サイトがある。 そこなら『グリードアイランド』の 手掛かりもあるだろうって。
Hmm? If we ignore the disciplined squads, they'll band together and cause us problems.
そうか！ ハンターライセンスを使うんだね。
Most likely, they'll start pairing disciplined and undisciplined squads together.
バカ！　自宅のパソコンを使ったら 住所がバレバレになるだろ！ ハンターライセンス狙いの小悪党が ぞろぞろ　島に集まっちまうぞ。
If we launch an indiscriminate
attack, it will result in chaos.
あっ　そっか。 こういうのは　公共のパソコン使って やるんだよ。
We should be able to eliminate
another three or four squads
ホテルとか　ネットカフェとか。
before the enemy tries another approach.
まぁ　何にせよ　アドレスが まだ分からないけどな。
I can already see their next move.
兄貴にロムカードを送れば 教えてくれる約束だ。 んで　もう１つが ヨークシンシティでのオークション。
If all goes well, we'll finish up
before reinforcements arrive.
えぇ!? ヨークシンシティっていったら…。
I hope
そう　クラピカ　レオリオと 再会を約束した場所。
things go that way.
兄貴は　ガセかもって 言ってたけど ある人物が そのゲームを何十本も
Okay, three hours! All done!
今年の　そのオークションに流す って情報があるらしい。 もしかして　その人物がジンかも。
Well, then... Get going.
ああ　そう考えると あながち　ガセじゃないかもな。 手に入れるためには 莫大な　お金が必要だね。
Here.
そういうこったな。
What, there are more of you?
いずれにせよ 俺達は ヨークシンシティに行く運命だったんだ
Don't hold back... Help yourselves.
クリアデータ入りのロムカードに ５００億の懸賞金を懸けてるのか。
It's on, Knuckle!
まさに　伝説だな。
Yeah, let's go!
フフン　面白い。
I'll take you both on at once! I won't say a word about
俺が伝説に終止符を打ってやる。
how you're condescending to us... We're more than happy to accept!
うわ　すっごい　ご馳走だね 何かあったの？
Let's go, Killua! Yeah!
それじゃあ！ いっただきます！
I have no time to waste playing
around with you kids.
ミトさん 俺　必ず　ジンを見つけるから！ ジンに会ったら また島に戻って来るからね！
Once they've accomplished
the tough task before them, they'll gain a confidence boost
that will spur their growth.
それまで元気でね！
However, to complete that task,
they must defeat me! And that ain't gonna happen
この後は　ゴンと…。 キルアの…。 ジンは　自分に会いたければ 捜してみろと言い　謎を残した この後は　ゴンと…。 キルアの…。 ハンサイクロペディア！ ジンは　自分に会いたければ 捜してみろと言い　謎を残した
Given his personality, he's probably already warmed
to these opponents...
ジンは　自分に会いたければ 捜してみろと言い　謎を残した ゴンは　その謎を解き 父親に会うため 再び故郷を離れ
I doubt he'd sell me out, but it's probable that he'll accidentally
say something he shouldn't.
キルアと共に　ヨークシンシティへ 向かったのだった
My chance will come after they leave.